Hello friends, please welcome to Insights.
Today we are going to discuss a
very important topic. I am going to
explain that whenever you are
admitted to a hospital for treatment and you do
not have a copy of your health card or health policy, then you will get
cashless treatment or you will have to
pay your bill in cash or
you will have to reverse it. This
question is a matter of concern for many people. So, to
answer this question, I have made this
video. Please like the video
and in this video, we will explain in detail what
you can do if you face such a problem and what is the
solution. So let's start the video.
[Music]
Whenever we are admitted to a hospital for treatment,
that condition is
an emergency condition. So,
what happens in that situation is that we do not remember whether
we have a health card or not. Many
problems or many such conditions occur that at that time,
things do
not come to mind.  And at that time, the health card
or the copy of the health insurance policy is
not available with us. When we
admit our patient in the hospital, then
what do we do in that condition?
When we take our patient inside the hospital, then it is
found out that there is a
TP facility there, then the admission there
enquires whether you have
a health card or not, so
what happens in that condition is that you do not have the
health card or the copy of the health policy,
but you say that it is
not available with us right now, we will
provide it later, but you are
not able to provide that thing even for 12 hours or 24 hours, then
what happens in that condition is
that the request is not able to
reach the insurance company and the insurance company has a
time period that whenever a
patient is admitted, then before 12 hours or 24
hours, an intimation should go to the insurance company. There is a
time of 24 hours to
inform the insurance company that
this patient has been admitted with this health card.  It is there and
we have sent this to you for its use, so that intimation is
very important but there are some conditions where the
patient's attendants do
not have a copy of his health card or health insurance policy,
so what can be done in that condition, let's say
if there is 24 hour treatment
and you do not have the health card available, then
what can I do in that, by making the
payment for 24 hours of a day and you can meet them,
take the receipt
and then book it, but if
a patient has to stay for more than one day
and he makes his card available to the hospital after 24 hours or 48 hours or
36 hours, then the
hospital can provide him cashless treatment in that condition also,
one of the conditions in it is that when the
hospital
sends a request to the insurance company, then the insurance company has the
power to query and
can ask for some additional documents and they have the power to ask that it has been
hours or 48 hours since you admitted the patient, you people have now
Why was the intimation done? You
can write a proper reason in it that when the patient
was admitted, the health
card was not available with the patient, due to which the hospital
delayed the intimation to you.
Mostly what happens is that the insurance
companies give approval, but even if they do
not give it, you
can definitely reverse it. At the time of discharge,
you can take your bill and attach it
to the discharge and take your payment from them.
Whatever your expenses are, it is
not that if you do
not have the health card within 24 hours or 12 hours, then
you cannot get cashless treatment. You can get it,
but its conditions are a little different and
you will have to make a small request to the hospital
staff through TP, even then it will be possible. So
in today's video, I was going to
tell you that your card can be
used even after 24 hours or
not. So, I hope this video has
cleared all your confusion.
For more such videos, please subscribe to our channel,
like the video
and  Still, if you guys have any
questions regarding this video or any other questions regarding this video, then
write to us in the comment section, we will definitely answer it, so see you
in the next video, till then,
goodbye.